<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WPs on Towards Computational Lexical Semantic Change Detection</title>
    <link>https://languagechange.org/wps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WPs on Towards Computational Lexical Semantic Change Detection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://languagechange.org/wps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wp1: Word Sense Induction</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/wps/word-sense-induction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/wps/word-sense-induction/</guid>
      <description>Automatically derived word senses are the basis for our continued work. For English, evaluated methods (Pantel and Lin, 2002; Brody and Lapata, 2009; Lau et al., 2012) exist and new methods are developed, the latest is the utilization of word embeddings (Nieto Piña and Johansson, 2015; Trask et al., 2015; Pelevina et al., 2016; Li and Jurafsky, 2015). For Swedish, these methods have not been tested at large scale and might perform less well due to smaller amounts of available text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wp2: Semantic Change Detection</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/wps/semantic-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/wps/semantic-change/</guid>
      <description>A rich tradition of cross-linguistic, detailed studies in lexical semantics has generated hypotheses that are ripe for further quantitative exploration made possible by the outcomes of this project. For example, synchronically: there are cognitively different kinds of temperature sensations, which form overt or covert sub-senses (Koptjevskaja-Tamm, 2015), that may be handled by different grammatical constructions (Pustet, 2015). Diachronically: word senses often go from describing external reality to internal perception (Traugott and Dasher, 2002); change often proceeds from a higher sensory modality to a lower (Viberg, 1980); perception verbs develop into cognitive verbs (Sweetser, 1991); or the exact hues denoted by Swedish color terms may change in a predictable fashion over time (Vejdemo, 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wp3: Lexical Replacement</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/wps/lexical-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/wps/lexical-replacement/</guid>
      <description>There are several impressive taxonomies that lists types of lexical replacement processes (Ullman, 1957), but these are mainly descriptive and make little attempt to predict what kind of lexical change might happen for a given concept. Some proposed general hypotheses are that nouns are replaced more readily than verbs, that more frequent words are insulated from replacement (Pagel et al., 2007) and that rich synonym networks speed up replacement (Vejdemo and Hörberg, 2016), hypotheses that we can investigate using quantitative approaches on large scale, diachronic text upon completion of this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wp4: Applications</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/wps/application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/wps/application/</guid>
      <description>This project will bring forth tools for computationally detecting lexical and semantic changes as well as word sense induction for Swedish. These tools give us a chance to study language changes in their own right but also overcome hurdles with research on historical text. We will bring together historical linguistics with NLP and data science, a unique collaboration needed to study semantic change and lexical replacements in full.
We believe the results of the project will advance the field in several research areas, offer benefits for researchers in the DHSS and lower the threshold for the public to make use of our textual resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>