<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Nina Tahmasebi</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Nina Tahmasebi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//localhost:1313/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Automatic Language Change Detection</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/languagechange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/languagechange/</guid>
      <description>Today, we lack computational tools for studying lexical and semantic changes at a large scale. Current methods are limited and require huge amounts of text. Studies on semantic change capture only main changes of a single word and offer no possibility to capture the interplay of change in a semantic field.
In this project, we aim to find automatic, corpus-based methods for detecting semantic change and lexical replacement for Swedish and English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culturomics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/culturomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/culturomics/</guid>
      <description>Recently, scholars have begun to draw on the massive amounts of text data made available through Google&amp;rsquo;s large-scale book digitization project in order to track the development of cultural concepts and words over the last two centuries, announcing a new field of research named &amp;ldquo;culturomics&amp;rdquo; by its originators.
However, these initial studies have been (rightly) criticized for not referring to relevant work in linguistics and language technology. Nevertheless, the basic premise of this endeavor is eminently timely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARCOMEM</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/arcomem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/arcomem/</guid>
      <description>The vision of the ARCOMEM project is to leverage the Wisdom of the Crowds for content appraisal, selection and preservation, so that archives reflect collective memory and social content perception
ARCOMEM is about memory institutions like archives, museums, and libraries in the age of the Social Web. Memory institutions are more important now than ever: as we face greater economic and environmental challenges we need our understanding of the past to help us navigate to a sustainable future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LiWA</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/liwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/liwa/</guid>
      <description>Web content plays an increasingly important role in the knowledge-based society, and the preservation and long-term accessibility of Web history has high value (e.g., for scholarly studies, market analyses, intellectual property disputes, etc.). There is strongly growing interest in its preservation by library and archival organizations as well as emerging industrial services. Web content characteristics (high dynamics, volatility, contributor and format variety) make adequate Web archiving a challenge.
LiWA will look beyond the pure “freezing” of Web content snapshots for a long time, transforming pure snapshot storage into a “Living” Web Archive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>