<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Historical Semantic Change on Towards Computational Lexical Semantic Change Detection</title>
    <link>https://languagechange.org/tags/historical-semantic-change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Historical Semantic Change on Towards Computational Lexical Semantic Change Detection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 09:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://languagechange.org/tags/historical-semantic-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3rd International Workshop on Computational Approaches to Historical Language Change 2022 (LChange&#39;22)</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/events/2022-acl-lchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/events/2022-acl-lchange/</guid>
      <description>The workshop builds upon its first iteration in 2019, and the second edition in 20121. It will be colocated with ACL 2022 in Dublin , Ireland, as a hybrid event. The workshop dates are not yet fixed but will be on May 26-28, or possibly both dates. This year, LChange will feature a shared task on semantic change detection for Spanish as one track of the workshop. We hope to make this third edition another resounding success!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd International Workshop on Computational Approaches to Historical Language Change 2021 (LChange&#39;21)</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/events/2021-acl-lchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/events/2021-acl-lchange/</guid>
      <description>The workshop builds upon its first iteration in 2019, where we received over 50 submissions and had over 65 attendees. Just like the first one, the second LChange workshop will be co-located with ACL (2021), and, pending on the situation, a hybrid event with possible online participation. We hope to make our second edition another resounding success!
The call for papers will be similar to last time: all aspects around computational approaches to historical language change with the focus on digital text corpora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SemEval-2020 Task 1: Unsupervised Lexical Semantic Change Detection</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/events/2020-semeval-2020-task1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/events/2020-semeval-2020-task1/</guid>
      <description>The workshop will be held as a part of the International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation 2020 December 12-13.
Our task description paper has been published. Videos and slides are now available.
More information on the task itself can be found on Codalab. Swedish testdata available here, postevaluation data for all participating languages available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turing workshop on automatic methods for lexical semantic change</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/events/2019-turing-lcworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/events/2019-turing-lcworkshop/</guid>
      <description>Words change their meaning over time, depending on a range of linguistic and extra-linguistic factors. Associating a word’s correct meaning in its historical context is a central challenge in diachronic research, and is relevant to a range of computational linguistics tasks, including information retrieval and semantic search on historical texts. In recent years, computational linguistics research has made great advances in the area of automatic detection of lexical semantic change, using a range of approaches varying from topic models to neural word embeddings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st International Workshop on Computational Approaches to Historical Language Change 2019</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/events/2019-acl-lcworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/events/2019-acl-lcworkshop/</guid>
      <description>The workshop was co-located with ACL 2019  in Florence, on August 2nd, 2019. We received over 50 submissions! and had over 65 attendees. Thank you all for making the workshop such a success!

The full list of accepted papers, together with the posters and presentations can be found here. The introduction and closing slides are here: LChange&amp;rsquo;19 Intro &amp;amp; Closing.
Schedule  August 2nd 2019  9:00–9:15 Introduction</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on Lexical Semantic Change</title>
      <link>https://languagechange.org/events/2019-acl-lcworkshop---copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://languagechange.org/events/2019-acl-lcworkshop---copy/</guid>
      <description>Languages change with time. While the study of meaning is not a new thing, the past few years have seen a lot of attention given to the computational tackling of particular tasks within (historical) semantics. Advances in NLP and the availability of massive textual corpora have made possible new research methods focused on lexical semantic change, using a range of approaches varying from topic models to neural word embeddings. Knowing what a word means at a particular moment of time is crucial for text-based research in the humanities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>